<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns:res="http://purl.org/vocab/resourcelist/schema#"
 xmlns:z="http://www.zotero.org/namespaces/export#"
 xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
 xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/">
    <z:UserItem rdf:about="47U7ZEBL">
        <res:resource rdf:resource="https://www.opp.purdue.edu/"/>
        <z:accessDate>2021-05-09 03:48:07</z:accessDate>
    </z:UserItem>
    <bibo:Webpage rdf:about="https://www.opp.purdue.edu/">
        <dcterms:title>Office of Professional Practice - Purdue University</dcterms:title>
        <bibo:uri>https://www.opp.purdue.edu/</bibo:uri>
        <dcterms:abstract>Known as the 'Cradle of Astronauts,' Purdue University's College of Engineering has produced 25 astronauts, including Neil Armstrong. The college also is home to such pioneers as Amelia Earhart and seven National Medal of Technology and Innovation recipients, as well as 25 past and present National Academy of Engineering members. Purdue Engineering hosts the largest academic propulsion lab in the world, the first all-digital nuclear reactor in the U.S., an NSF Engineering Research Center, an SRC-DARPA center, and a NASA Space Technology Research Institute. The largest of the top 10 U.S. engineering colleges, Purdue Engineering is the nation's No. 1 producer of graduate engineers of any public research university and No. 2 producer of undergraduate engineers of any university annually. Purdue Engineering is ranked No. 8 for graduate engineering, No. 9 for undergraduate engineering and No. 5 for online graduate engineering in the nation by U.S. News &amp; World Report. For startup creation, the Wall Street Journal listed Purdue as the No. 1 U.S. public university and No. 6 globally. Purdue Engineering research has garnered more than 700 U.S. patents.</dcterms:abstract>
        <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
        <dcterms:isPartOf>
            <bibo:Website>
                <dcterms:title>Office of Professional Practice - Purdue University</dcterms:title>
            </bibo:Website>
        </dcterms:isPartOf>
    </bibo:Webpage>
</rdf:RDF>
