<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns:res="http://purl.org/vocab/resourcelist/schema#"
 xmlns:z="http://www.zotero.org/namespaces/export#"
 xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
 xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/"
 xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/">
    <z:UserItem rdf:about="98GX9WPS">
        <res:resource rdf:resource="https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/SIL-VER-JUBILEE-OF-MY-DISPUTE-WITH-FISHERl-Neyman/2e0dd2cd1d9d41c9da636adfd1560ef5945b896f"/>
        <z:accessDate>2021-03-21 06:50:05</z:accessDate>
    </z:UserItem>
    <bibo:Webpage rdf:about="https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/SIL-VER-JUBILEE-OF-MY-DISPUTE-WITH-FISHERl-Neyman/2e0dd2cd1d9d41c9da636adfd1560ef5945b896f">
        <dcterms:title>SIL VER JUBILEE OF MY DISPUTE WITH FISHERl</dcterms:title>
        <dcterms:abstract>After publishing Sir Ronald Fisher's article [1], the Editors of the Operations Research Society of Japan called my attention to Sir Ronald's uncomplimentary references to my work and offered to publish a reply. The first expressions of disapproval of my work were published by Fisher [2J in 1935. During the intervening quarter of a century Sir Ronald honored my ideas with his incessant attention and a steady flow of printed matter published in many countries on several continents. All these writings, equally uncomplimentary to me and to those with whom I was working, refer to only five early papers, [3J to [7J, all published between 1933 and 1938. In general, scientific disputes are useful even if, at times, they are somewhat bitter. For example, the exchange of opinions and the studies surrounding the definition of probability given by Richard von Mises, clarified the thinking considerably. On the one hand, this dispute brought out the superiority of Kolmogoroff's axiomatization [8J of the theory. On the other hand, the same dispute established firmly von Mises' philosophical outlook on &quot;frequentist&quot; probability as a useful tool in indeterministic studies of phenomena. There are many similar examples in the history of science. Thus., at least in its early stages, my</dcterms:abstract>
        <bibo:uri>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/SIL-VER-JUBILEE-OF-MY-DISPUTE-WITH-FISHERl-Neyman/2e0dd2cd1d9d41c9da636adfd1560ef5945b896f</bibo:uri>
        <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
        <dcterms:creator rdf:nodeID="n1167"/>
        <bibo:authorList>
           <rdf:Seq><rdf:li rdf:nodeID="n1167"/></rdf:Seq>
        </bibo:authorList>
        <dcterms:isPartOf>
           <bibo:Website><dcterms:date>2009</dcterms:date></bibo:Website>
        </dcterms:isPartOf>
    </bibo:Webpage>
    <foaf:Person rdf:nodeID="n1167">
       <foaf:givenName>J.</foaf:givenName><foaf:surname>Neyman</foaf:surname>
    </foaf:Person>
</rdf:RDF>
