<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns:ctag="http://commontag.org/ns#"
 xmlns:z="http://www.zotero.org/namespaces/export#"
 xmlns:res="http://purl.org/vocab/resourcelist/schema#"
 xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
 xmlns:address="http://schemas.talis.com/2005/address/schema#"
 xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
 xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/">
    <z:UserItem rdf:about="AAQL8VD6">
        <ctag:tagged rdf:nodeID="n3924"/>
        <z:repository>Library Catalog (Blacklight)</z:repository>
        <ctag:tagged rdf:nodeID="n3920"/>
        <ctag:tagged rdf:nodeID="n3921"/>
        <ctag:tagged>
           <ctag:AutoTag><ctag:label>Robots</ctag:label></ctag:AutoTag>
        </ctag:tagged>
        <ctag:tagged>
           <ctag:AutoTag><ctag:label>Human factors</ctag:label></ctag:AutoTag>
        </ctag:tagged>
        <ctag:tagged rdf:nodeID="n3920"/>
        <res:resource rdf:resource="urn:isbn:9780190652968"/>
        <ctag:tagged>
            <ctag:AutoTag>
               <ctag:label>BUSINESS &amp; ECONOMICS</ctag:label>
            </ctag:AutoTag>
        </ctag:tagged>
        <ctag:tagged>
           <ctag:AutoTag><ctag:label>Business Ethics</ctag:label></ctag:AutoTag>
        </ctag:tagged>
        <ctag:tagged rdf:nodeID="n3920"/>
        <ctag:tagged rdf:nodeID="n3921"/>
        <ctag:tagged rdf:nodeID="n3920"/>
        <ctag:tagged rdf:nodeID="n3924"/>
        <ctag:tagged>
           <ctag:AutoTag><ctag:label>Electronic books</ctag:label></ctag:AutoTag>
        </ctag:tagged>
    </z:UserItem>
    <bibo:Book rdf:about="urn:isbn:9780190652968">
        <dcterms:publisher>
            <foaf:Organization>
                <address:localityName>New York, NY</address:localityName>
                <foaf:name>Oxford University Press</foaf:name>
            </foaf:Organization>
        </dcterms:publisher>
        <bibo:isbn13>9780190652968</bibo:isbn13>
        <dcterms:abstract>The robot population is rising on Earth and other planets. (Mars is inhabited entirely by robots.) As robots slip into more domains of human life--from the operating room to the bedroom--they take on our morally important tasks and decisions, as well as create new risks from psychological to physical. This makes it all the more urgent to study their ethical, legal, and policy impacts. To help the robotics industry and broader society, we need to not only press ahead on a wide range of issues, but also identify new ones emerging as quickly as the field is evolving. For instance, where military robots had received much attention in the past (and are still controversial today), this volume looks toward autonomous cars here as an important case study that cuts across diverse issues, from liability to psychology to trust and more. And because robotics feeds into and is fed by AI, the Internet of Things, and other cognate fields, robot ethics must also reach into those domains, too. Expanding these discussions also means listening to new voices; robot ethics is no longer the concern of a handful of scholars. Experts from different academic disciplines and geographical areas are now playing vital roles in shaping ethical, legal, and policy discussions worldwide. So, for a more complete study, the editors of this volume look beyond the usual suspects for the latest thinking. Many of the views as represented in this cutting-edge volume are provocative--but also what we need to push forward in unfamiliar territory. -- Provided by publisher</dcterms:abstract>
        <dcterms:title>Robot ethics 2.0: from autonomous cars to artificial intelligence</dcterms:title>
        <bibo:numPages>1</bibo:numPages>
        <bibo:lccn>EBOOKS</bibo:lccn>
        <z:extra>OCLC: on1001434777</z:extra>
        <bibo:isbn13>9780190652982</bibo:isbn13>
        <dcterms:date>2017</dcterms:date>
        <bibo:shortTitle>Robot ethics 2.0</bibo:shortTitle>
        <bibo:editor rdf:nodeID="n3916"/>
        <bibo:editorList>
            <rdf:Seq>
                <rdf:li rdf:nodeID="n3916"/>
                <rdf:li rdf:nodeID="n3918"/>
                <rdf:li rdf:nodeID="n3919"/>
            </rdf:Seq>
        </bibo:editorList>
        <bibo:editor rdf:nodeID="n3918"/>
        <bibo:editor rdf:nodeID="n3919"/>
    </bibo:Book>
    <foaf:Person rdf:nodeID="n3916">
       <foaf:givenName>Patrick</foaf:givenName><foaf:surname>Lin</foaf:surname>
    </foaf:Person>
    <foaf:Person rdf:nodeID="n3918">
       <foaf:givenName>Keith</foaf:givenName><foaf:surname>Abney</foaf:surname>
    </foaf:Person>
    <foaf:Person rdf:nodeID="n3919">
       <foaf:givenName>Ryan</foaf:givenName><foaf:surname>Jenkins</foaf:surname>
    </foaf:Person>
    <ctag:AutoTag rdf:nodeID="n3920">
       <ctag:label>Robotics</ctag:label>
    </ctag:AutoTag>
    <ctag:AutoTag rdf:nodeID="n3921">
       <ctag:label>Moral and ethical aspects</ctag:label>
    </ctag:AutoTag>
    <ctag:AutoTag rdf:nodeID="n3924">
       <ctag:label>Social aspects</ctag:label>
    </ctag:AutoTag>
    <z:UserItem rdf:about="#item_2">
        <res:resource>
            <bibo:Note>
                <z:note>I. Moral and Legal Responsibility -- Autonomous Vehicles and Moral Uncertainty / Vikram Bhargava and Tae Wan Kim -- Ethics Settings for Autonomous Vehicles Jason Millar -- Autonomy and Responsibility in Hybrid Systems: The Example of Autonomous Cars / Wulf Loh and Janina Sombetzki -- Imputing Driverhood: Applying a Reasonable Driver Standard to Accidents Caused by Autonomous Vehicles / Jeffery K. Gurney -- Liability Law for Present and Future Robotics Technology / Trevor N. White and Seth D. Baum -- Skilled Perception, Authenticity, and the Case Against Automation / David Zoller -- II. Trust and Human-Robot Interactions -- Could a Robot Care? It's All in the Movement / Darian Meacham and Matthew Studley -- Robot Friends for Autistic Children: Monopoly Money or Counterfeit Currency? / Alexis Elder -- Pediatric Robotics and Ethics: The Robot Is Ready to See You Now, But Should It Be Trusted? / Jason Borenstein, Ayanna Howard, and Alan R. Wagner -- Trust and Human-Robot Interactions / Jesse Kirkpatrick, Erin N. Hahn, and Amy J. Haufler -- White Lies on Silver Tongues: Why Robots Need to Deceive (and How) / Alistair M.C. Isaac and Will Bridewell -- &quot;Who's Johnny?&quot; Anthropomorphic Framing in Human-Robot Interaction, Integration, and Policy / Kate Darling -- III. Applications: From Love to War -- Lovotics: Human-Robot Love and Sex Relationships / Adrian David Cheok, Kasun Karunanayaka, and Emma Yann Zhang -- Church-Turing Lovers / Piotr Boltuc -- The Internet of Things and Dual Layers of Ethical Concern / Adam Henschke -- Challenges to Engineering Moral Reasoners: Time and Context / Michal Klincewicz -- When Robots Should Do the Wrong Thing / Brian Talbot, Ryan Jenkins, and Duncan Purves -- Military Robots and the Likelihood of Armed Combat / Leonard Kahn -- IV. The Future of AI and Robotics -- Testing the Moral Status of Artificial Beings, or &quot;I'm Going to Ask You Some Questions&quot; / Michael LaBossiere -- Artificial Identity / James DiGiovanna -- Superintelligence as Superethical / Steve Petersen -- Artificial Intelligence and the Ethics of Self-Learning Robots / Shannon Vallor and George Bekey -- Robots and Space Ethics / Keith Abney -- On the Unabomber and Robots: The Need for a Philosophy of Technology Geared Toward Human Ends / Jai Galliott -- Biosketches</z:note>
            </bibo:Note>
        </res:resource>
    </z:UserItem>
</rdf:RDF>
