<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns:res="http://purl.org/vocab/resourcelist/schema#"
 xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
 xmlns:z="http://www.zotero.org/namespaces/export#"
 xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/"
 xmlns:sc="http://umbel.org/umbel/sc/">
    <z:UserItem rdf:about="LV2VVEMP">
        <res:resource rdf:resource="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=John_Searle&amp;oldid=1021102901"/>
        <dcterms:rights>Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License</dcterms:rights>
        <z:repository>Wikipedia</z:repository>
        <z:accessDate>2021-05-09 03:03:14</z:accessDate>
    </z:UserItem>
    <bibo:Article rdf:about="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=John_Searle&amp;oldid=1021102901">
        <dcterms:title>John Searle</dcterms:title>
        <bibo:uri>https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=John_Searle&amp;oldid=1021102901</bibo:uri>
        <z:extra>Page Version ID: 1021102901</z:extra>
        <dcterms:language>en</dcterms:language>
        <dcterms:abstract>John Rogers Searle (; born July 31, 1932) is an American philosopher. He was Willis S. and Marion Slusser Professor Emeritus of the Philosophy of Mind and Language and Professor of the Graduate School at the University of California, Berkeley until June 2019, when his emeritus status was revoked for having violated the university’s sexual harassment policies. Widely noted for his contributions to the philosophy of language, philosophy of mind, and social philosophy, he began teaching at UC Berkeley in 1959. 
As an undergraduate at the University of Wisconsin–Madison, Searle was secretary of &quot;Students against Joseph McCarthy&quot;. He received all his university degrees, BA, MA, and DPhil, from the University of Oxford, where he held his first faculty positions. Later, at UC Berkeley, he became the first tenured professor to join the 1964–1965 Free Speech Movement. In the late 1980s, Searle challenged the restrictions of Berkeley's 1980 rent stabilization ordinance. Following what came to be known as the California Supreme Court's &quot;Searle Decision&quot; of 1990, Berkeley changed its rent control policy, leading to large rent increases between 1991 and 1994.
In 2000 Searle received the Jean Nicod Prize; in 2004, the National Humanities Medal; and in 2006, the Mind &amp; Brain Prize. He was elected to the American Philosophical Society in 2010. Searle's early work on speech acts, influenced by J. L. Austin and Ludwig Wittgenstein, helped establish his reputation. His notable concepts include the &quot;Chinese room&quot; argument against &quot;strong&quot; artificial intelligence.</dcterms:abstract>
        <dcterms:isPartOf>
            <sc:Encyclopedia>
                <dcterms:title>Wikipedia</dcterms:title>
                <dcterms:date>2021-05-02T22:42:19Z</dcterms:date>
                <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/ReferenceSource"/>
            </sc:Encyclopedia>
        </dcterms:isPartOf>
    </bibo:Article>
</rdf:RDF>
